<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<xml>
  <body>
    <div>
      <p><persName idref="030854385">Alexander Brassicanus</persName>Brassi!] canus, Iureconsultus, 11 S. P. D...— Viennae Austriae  ex Regio Collegio.! Anno a nato Iesu M. D. XXXI. Mense Decembri. ( Epistola nuncupatoria, 3 pp.)  fol. L 4a, nouveau titre pour Bessarion. Au verso: Reverendo I] ac  ervdito patri, D. Vlde!! richo Fabro, Coenobii Dominici Sepul!] chri in  Denckendorff Praeposito... Iohannes! <persName idref="030854385">Alexander Brassicanus</persName>!] Iure¬  consultus!! S. D. P...— Vien! nae Austriae, Anno a nato Iesu  M. D. XXXII. 1! Mensis Ianuarii die III.( 3 pp.). Ce traité n’ a pas de  titre courant.  R. 102.200. Prov.: Don BM Hambourg, <date>1871</date>.  BN Paris: C. 1970( 6).  2067  <persName>SALTZMANN</persName>Joh. Rod. Voir: SPACH Israel, Theses medicae.  <placeName>Strasbourg</placeName>, A. Bertram, 1595. RI01, 564( 15)  <persName idref="169796574">SAMPSON Thomas</persName> <placeName>Strasbourg</placeName>, 1554  A letter to the trew professors of Christes Gos- pell,  inhabitinge in the Parisye off! Allhallowis, in Bredstrete in  <placeName>London</placeName>, made by ThomasSampson, sometime! their  Pastore.  2. Corin. 6.( 3 lignes.).  Imprynted at <placeName>Strasburgh</placeName>in <placeName>Elsasz</placeName>at the signe of the  golden Bi-bell, Jn the moneth of Auguste. the yeare of  our Lord. 1554.( Verso blanc.)  In-8°, car. goth., 14 ff. non ch. et 4 ff. blancs, sign. A- B, réclames,  notes marg., init. fleurie T.  R. 100.552. Prov.: L. Rosenthal, Munich, 16/11I, 1887; 30 M.  Incompl. fol. Bi et Bij manquent.  Pollard A. W.&amp; amp; G. R. Redgrave, A short- tille catalogue of books  printed in England, Scotland&amp; amp; Ireland and of English books printed  abroad 1475- 1640( <placeName>London</placeName><date>1926</date>): Londres, British Museum; Oxford,  Bibl. Bodleiana; Cambridge, BU; Bibl. Sir R. L. Harmsworth. Le titre  diffère un peu de celui de notre exemplaire. Entre parenthèse le catalogue  donne:[ <placeName>London</placeName>, H. <persName>Singleton</persName>?] avec point d’ interrogation.  Bibliographie. Voir: Schottenloher II, n° 18847a-18847b.  2068  <persName idref="068528132">SAMUEL Maroccanus</persName>(( Rabbi)) <placeName>Strasbourg</placeName>, J. Herwagen, 1523  Quod!! Iudaei Messiam, quiuenit, ceu uenturum, timore!  expectent. Libellus sane!! doctus Rabi!! Samuelis...  A la fin: <placeName>Argentorati</placeName>apud <persName idref="168458462">Iohannem</persName>Hervagium,  IIII. Nonas Iulias. Anno Domini. I1 M. D. XXIII.( Verso  blanc.)  In-8°, car. ital., 32 ff. non ch., sign. A- D, titre courant, réclames, titre  encadré: en haut Dieu le père dans les nuages, à côté de lui Saint Pierre et  </p>
    </div>
  </body>
</xml>
