<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<xml>
  <body>
    <div>
      <p><persName idref="032086229">PALUDANUS PETRUS</persName>: Sermones thesauri novi de tempore.  <placeName>Strasbourg</placeName>, Martin Flach, 1491, in- fol.  Copinger 5417, Schmidt VI, 38, Voulliéme: <placeName>Berlin</placeName>2492, 3.  K 3300. Prov.: Don de la ville de <placeName>Heilbronn</placeName>, 1872. Rel. anc.  364  <persName idref="032086229">PALUDANUS PETRUS</persName>: Sermones thesauri novi de tempore.  <placeName>Strasbourg</placeName>, Martin Flach, 1493, in- fol.  Copinger 5418, Günther: <placeName>Leipzig</placeName>2760, Madsen 3019, Schmidt  VI, 46.  K 3300a. Prov.: L. Rosenthal, Munich, 16. <date>X. 1888</date>, 18 M.  Notes mss. Au bas du f. a2a:« Ex Bibliotheca S. Georgii  Dinckelspyhlo 1704.» Notes mss. Rel. anc.  365  <persName idref="032086229">PALUDANUS PETRUS</persName>: Sermones thesauri novi de tempore.  <placeName>Strasbourg</placeName>, Martin Flach, 1497, in- fol.  Copinger 5420, Schmidt VI, 62.  K 3302. Prov.: Don du prince de <placeName>Bentheim</placeName>, <date>1871</date>. Notes mss.  Incomplet, sign. g5-m2 manquent.  366  PANORMITANUS abbas. Voir: <persName idref="06852837X">Tudeschis Nicolaus</persName>de.  PARATUS: Sermones de tempore et de sanctis.( <placeName>Strasbourg</placeName>,  <persName>J. Grüninger</persName>), s. d., in- fol.  Hain 12406, Madsen 3041, Voulliéme: <placeName>Berlin</placeName>2517.  K 2811. Prov.; B N Munich, 22. L. <date>1880</date>, 1 M 30. Au- dessus du  titre:« Georgius prantb». Au- dessous:« Georgius präntellius  parochus». Au haut du f. a2a:« Sum ex libris Mgri Caspari  Karneri SS theol. studiosi.» Notes mss. Rel. anc.  367  PARATUS: Sermones de tempore et de sanctis. <placeName>Strasbourg</placeName>,  impr. du Jordanus(— G. Husner)), 1er sept. 1487,in-2°.  Hain 12411, Proctor 613.  K 2813. Prov.; B N Munich, 22. I. <date>1880</date>, 3 M.  A la suite de Guilhelmus, Postilla, 1489. K 1865.  368  PARENTINIS. Voir: <persName>Bernardinus</persName>de Parentinis.  77  </p>
    </div>
  </body>
</xml>
