<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<xml>
  <body>
    <div>
      <p><date>1880</date>, 30 M. Notes mss.  Pars I et II dans un volume. Au haut du 1er f. du 1er vol.:  Ad. P. P. Franciscanos Vellhausij. Bib.». Rel anc. pour le  1er vol.  3e vol. incomplet, manque ff. 1 et 2. A l’ intérieur du 1er plat  du 2° et 3e vol. exlibris avec la devise:« Honos Erit  huic quoque Luto.», et en bas:« Andreae Felicis OEfely.  Monacensis.»  476  <persName>VINCENTIUS</persName><persName idref="027186997">VINCENTIUS BELLOVACENSIS</persName>: Speculum historiale, Pars I- IV.  Copinger III. 6245, Madsen 4160, Proctor 254, Voulliéme:  <placeName>Berlin</placeName>2131; Walter: <placeName>Sélestat</placeName>497.  K 3721. Prov.; Don de la ville de <placeName>Trèves</placeName>, <date>1871</date>, dont le  cachet se trouve au bas du 1er f. Rel. anc. Notes mss.  2e ex. K. 3721a. Prov.; Don d’ <persName>Oswald Ottendorfer</persName>, New-York,  31. VII. <date>1885</date>. A l’ intérieur du 1er plat, fiche découpée d’ un  catalogue anglais: First edition... large initial, coloured let¬  ters leightened with gold,... a most splendid specimen of  printing in its very earliest infancy. Very fine copy. Original  stamped monastic binding.... Dibdin and other bibliographers  state that it was printed at <placeName>Strasbury</placeName>by <persName>J. Mentelin</persName>about the  year <date>1470</date>, although a previous possessor has titled it« Faust,  <placeName>Mayence</placeName><date>1474</date>.» It is excessively rare, and no copy exists in  the British Museum or the Spencer Library. This volume  formed part of the treasures of the late library at <placeName>Strasburg</placeName>,  which was entirely destroyed during the late seige. This and  a very few other volumes alone being saved from total  destruction. It ought to be in a national library.» Au verso  du f. de garde:« Editio antiquissima, typis Mentellianis  impressa. Cat. Palm V, n° 1862. Liber rarissimus. Theod. de  Mann( 2) pos.» Rel, anc.  477  <persName>VINCENTIUS</persName><persName idref="027186997">VINCENTIUS BELLOVACENSIS</persName>PSEUDO-: Speculum morale. ( Strasbourg, <persName>J. Mentelin</persName>, pas après 9 <date>nov.</date>1476), in- fol.  Copinger 6252, Proctor 214, Madsen 4162, Voulliéme: <placeName>Berlin</placeName> 2109, Schorbach: N° 37.  K 3729. Prov.: Bibl. F. A. Menke, Brême, 1873. Notes mss.  478  <persName>VINCENTIUS</persName><persName idref="027186997">VINCENTIUS BELLOVACENSIS</persName>: Speculum naturale.( Stras¬  bourg, impr. R.(— Ad. Rusch), vers <date>1470</date>), in- fol.  Copinger III. 6256, Madsen 4166, Proctor 255, Voulliéme: Ber¬  lin 2132. Walter; <placeName>Sélestat</placeName>499.  100  </p>
    </div>
  </body>
</xml>
